(Prince Milpoong, Lee Tan)
This feels...
a bit strange.
Go and find out.
Why isn't anyone coming?
- Yes, Your Majesty.
Prince Milpoong.
Yoon Yeong.
Where were you?
I thought you left me.
I guess I was wrong.
Right? You came back, right?
Don't worry.
Our reinforcements will gather here.
There are no reinforcements.
This is a trap.
Lee Yin Jwa deserted you.
No.
- That's not true, Yoon Yeong.
- We must go.
The royal forces are coming.
If you stay here, you will die.
Capture Prince Milpoong alive!
- Yes, sir!
This is useless. It is over now.
If you want to live,
you should run away with me.
His Majesty has arrived.
(King Yeongjo)
I finally meet you.
Leader of the rebels.
Lee Yin Jwa.
(Lee Yin Jwa, Namin)
How dare you harm
the innocent people...
and dishonor this country?
I will ensure...
to deal with your horrible crime...
with the death penalty.
You are an unworthy king.
- How dare you?
- Finally,
I meet you too.
How dare you speak that way?
How dare I?
Who is this man?
How is he different from me?
The only thing I am guilty of...
is that I was born a Namin.
That is all.
Shut your mouth!
Just behead me.
I will die anyway.
I might as well die here.
However,
I raised an army for a good reason.
Just because you're a Namin,
you can't do anything in this world!
All I tried to do was to change...
the rotten world I'm living in.
Your Majesty, please give me
your orders.
- I shall kill this man...
- Stop.
- Your Majesty.
- Is that really...
the only reason?
Did you kill innocent people...
and bring chaos into this world...
just because of that?
I'm asking you.
Yes.
You are right, Lee Yin Jwa.
You and I...
are not different.
My only fault...
is that I was born of a peasant.
- Your Majesty.
- That is right.
The person who knows how you feel
better than anyone else...
is the king you tried to...
dethrone.
That's me.
However,
you are wrong.
That is not how...
you change the world.
There is another way.
I am...
determined...
to prove that.
(Episode 23: Long-standing Hope)
You just wait.
I will kill you...
along with your other comrades.
- Keep a close eye on him.
- Yes, sir.
Your Majesty.
Have they not arrested
Prince Milpoong yet?
He shouldn't have gone too far.
Block all the ferry narrows
and search every corner!
- Yes, sir!
Stay here. I will find a way
to escape.
No.
Why?
Why must I run away?
- Prince Milpoong.
- I am the king.
I will go back to where I belong.
The king? Wake up.
You were never worthy of that title.
It was not just the Patriarchs
and Lee Yin Jwa. I also...
used you.
You were pathetic and stupid.
Every time I praised you...
and said you deserve to be king,
you were so easy to manipulate.
Yoon Yeong.
Do you want to be taken advantage
of by people like me...
and die in vain?
Are you going to be a clown
until the last moment...
and end up dying?
How is the situation out there?
Where are the soldiers?
They are everywhere.
Lee Yin Jwa's remaining forces...
were arrested too.
What?
This will not do.
I brought you here...
because Dal Moon asked me.
But I can't do any more than this.
Find me a boat
to the Qing Dynasty...
without telling Dal Moon.
But...
No. That is too dangerous.
This is half of my possession.
I will give you the rest...
if you find me a ship.
A king?
Wake up.
You were never worthy of that title.
It's not just the Patriarchs
Lee Yin Jwa. Even I...
used you...
because you were pathetic
and stupid.
All I had to do was praise you
a little...
and you were so easy to manipulate.
If you realized
that you weren't worth that much,
you shouldn't have
acted up like that.
No. No.
Don't give up on me.
Please.
I'll do anything you want.
When I see people like you,
I realize that social status
is a chimera.
You realize...
that most people are just animals...
who can talk.
Speaking of bloodlines,
you are not even the son
of a king.
You're an indirect descent.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Father.
How can I trust someone like you?
Who would think you're a prince?
No. They are all wrong.
They are all wrong.
I am the true king of this kingdom.
- Your Majesty.
The entire kingdom...
will drive out the fake king...
and rise up...
to welcome the real king.
This kingdom...
belongs to Prince Sohyeon...
and my father.
My father...
I came to meet His Majesty.
Announce my arrival.
Your Majesty,
are you really going
to give the order?
Do as I've told you.
But Your Majesty...
Your Majesty, Inspector
Park Moon Soo of Saheonbu is here.
Let him in.
Come on in.
Your Majesty, where is
Prince Milpoong?
The Five Military Bases
are pursuing him now.
He will never escape.
By the way Moon Soo,
you should go back to Saheonbu.
- Back to Saheonbu?
- Yes.
In the palace...
and Saheonbu,
another long-standing war...
will begin.
Is anyone outside?
Did you call for me, Your Majesty?
I'm summoning a meeting
at the Hall of Convenience now.
Tell all senior officials...
that they must attend.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Who are they?
Red robes mean
they are senior officials.
But I don't recognize them.
Isn't that Cho Duk Soo
from the Namin Party?
What? Namin Party?
Namin Party?
That's right.
They're the Namins
who left the palace.
Exactly.
Why have they entered the palace?
His Majesty has arrived.
- Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
My apologies, but how could you...
- bring these...
- If you're sorry,
it's better to stop talking.
The topic for today's meeting...
is what you want to ask.
If you wait, I'll kindly...
give you the answers.
Thanks to your loyalty,
we could arrest
the rebellion leader Lee Yin Jwa...
and his remaining men.
This was possible...
mainly because...
of the people of this country...
who gave up their lives...
and all of you who committed
yourselves...
regardless of your
political background.
I will...
never forget that.
With that strength,
I will overcome the pain
caused by the revolt...
and lead this kingdom...
into a new Joseon...
without wavering.
As the first step to that,
I will reorganize the palace
by renewing personnel.
Chief Royal Secretary.
Read out my order.
Yes, Your Majesty.
[Kocowa Ver] SBS E45 'Haechi'
"An Old Hope"
-♥ Ruo Xi ♥-
Today,
I appoint new personnel.
To take care of the confusion...
among the people by the revolt,
Cho Duk Soo,
former Hongmoongwan officer...
will be sent to Gyeongsang Province
as recruiting officer.
(Recruiting officer:
officer who recruits new soldiers)
Inscrutable are the King's favors.
Also,
as Chungcheong Province's
recruiting officer,
the former vice minister Yoo Soon...
You can't do this.
You can't do this, Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
what right do they have?
Continue, chief royal secretary.
Yes, Your Majesty.
As Chungcheong Province's
recruiting officer,
the former vice minister...
Yoo Soon will be appointed.
Inscrutable are the King's favors.
And former minister
Yoon Heon Joong...
will be appointed
as dispatch officer.
(Dispatch Officer: inspects officers
and listens to complaints)
Inscrutable are the King's favors.
Whatever your duty is,
show your loyalty in fulfilling it.
- Inscrutable are the King's favors.
Cho Duk Soo?
Yoo Soon? Your Majesty.
They don't deserve...
to stand in this palace.
I can't accept this order.
What did they accomplish...
to take on such important duties?
Please hear our words.
- Please hear our words.
They're the Namins.
Some of them might have...
worked with Lee Yin Jwa.
You should rather punish them.
How could you appoint them?
This is ridiculous!
Work with Lee Yin Jwa?
Watch what you're saying!
He didn't say anything wrong.
What nonsense are you saying?
So? How are the senior officials
reacting?
Both Patriarchs and Disciples...
are furious.
Appointing Namins would seem
preposterous to them.
The King seems to be starting
a difficult fight.
The whole palace...
might become his enemy.
Your Majesty,
how about taking
things a bit slowly?
We just resolved the crisis...
and we have not arrested
Prince Milpoong yet.
There is still disorder...
That is why we should carry on
with it now.
The state of confusion...
is the right time to carry on
with the reform.
What do you mean?
I am still a helplessly powerless
king.
The only thing I can rely on...
is public opinion.
The revolt ended a few days ago...
and the officials are in a turf war.
What would the people think?
Public opinion...
(Lee Gwang Jwa, Minister of War,
Disciples)
Are you trying to gain power
by moving public opinion?
Thousands were killed in the revolt.
They are all families...
and relatives of the people.
This is the state we are in...
and the officials are protesting...
when I suggested...
we appoint Namins.
The fury...
will certainly...
spread outside the palace.
Court Lady Cheon.
Court Lady Heo, how is His Majesty?
May I see him for a moment?
It will not be possible
at the moment.
He has been in a meeting
all the while.
You would know too.
The palace is in an uproar.
The disciples defended the palace
during the revolt.
Then,
how can he give the position
to Namins?
The Patriarchs have an advantage
over us anyway.
We cannot step back any further.
We Disciples...
are losing the turf war.
Is that what you want to protest?
My lord, that is not what
I am saying.
Go on. What else...
do you want me to tell the King?
Is it true that you agreed to
appointing the Namins?
That was the only way...
to quench the revolt.
The King will demand us...
to hand over the next offices.
How can the head of
the Patriarchs...
make such a compromise?
It was not compromise.
(Min Jin Heon, Chairman of Congress,
Patriarchs)
It was politics.
That was the better choice.
I should not have done so...
as the head of Patriarchs.
I do not deserve to lead you any
longer.
I will resign.
Will that satisfy you?
My lord.
- My lord.
What are we to do?
Go and summon Chief Inspector
of Saheonbu.
- Right now, hurry.
- Yes, my lord.
We heard the news from the palace,
Chief Inspector.
Gather all the officials
of Daejangcheong immediately.
Yes.
It will be Saheonbu.
Saheonbu will start moving first
since it has judicial power.
Saganwon and Hongmoongwan...
will give support.
The Patriarchs have controlled
the three agencies for that purpose.
I am preparing for that.
You are...
in a difficult situation
because of me.
That is not true, Your Majesty.
I am rather...
feeling relieved.
You are the one in a difficult
situation.
Fair appointment regardless of
political orientation...
and equity.
That is a dream...
I once dreamed of.
It is just that I realized...
that it is impossible in reality.
It is impossible?
You will find out soon.
It is possible...
to progress for a short moment.
But politics reverts...
to its original position.
So soon you will realize...
that you had dreamed of...
an unattainable dream.
Wait.
Wait a moment.
We can progress for a short
moment...
but will fall back eventually?
Then why...
did you help me?
If you think...
it will be of no use?
Why?
That is...
The reason is that...
Min Jin Heon.
The man who entrusted Yoon Yeong...
did not come for the money?
Not yet.
He is a greedy man
and that is why I volunteered.
- But for some reason...
- Can we get in touch with him?
He is an itinerant merchant
who does not have an address.
Then we do not know where he lives?
We will find a boat soon.
Then we will go to Qing and...
You deserted me too.
Did you not?
I was easy to take advantage of
because I was dumb and pathetic?
That is nonsense.
Did you really think I would not
know how other people thought of me?
Everyone laughed at me
and mocked me from behind.
They treated me like
an insect.
But in case I became king,
they flattered me...
in front of me. Am I wrong?
But it did not matter.
I could just become king.
When I became the king,
they would not laugh at me
even from behind.
And you...
would hold me sincerely.
I am sorry.
The one who made you like this...
is me.
So give me a chance too.
So I can forgive at least
one person...
just like I was...
forgiven by someone.
Tomorrow at Hall of Convenience,
the senior officials will probably
not show up.
If that happens,
I will issue the order.
I will do as you say.
Thank you for your decision,
Chief Justice.
From tomorrow,
it will be war again.
Why do you not get some sleep?
- No, I have things to...
- It is because...
I am tired.
Oh, I am sorry.
I did not think of that.
You are working your old subject...
too harshly.
Excuse me. May I see Court Lady Heo
for a moment?
Yeo Ji.
Why are you at the palace
at this hour?
Really?
You made these snacks just for me?
You seemed to be working late,
so I was going to give it
to Court Lady Heo.
Then open it. Let's take a look.
No, Your Majesty.
- I will just...
- Why?
You said it's for me.
But I'm shy.
Did you...
Did you really make this yourself?
Do they look weird?
It was my first time
so the shapes are...
No.
I thought...
you were just a tomboy,
but this is impressive.
Do you mean that, Your Majesty?
Are they okay?
Not just okay.
This is...
What is it, Your Majesty?
No... Well...
Are you choking?
Should I get you some water?
No, it is okay.
It is bearable.
It is bearable?
Goodness, does it taste that bad?
Goodness, Your Majesty.
Yeo Ji,
did you not say...
you got thoroughly prepared
before coming into the palace?
Well, yes. I tried my best...
You said your cooking skills...
are much better...
than the court ladies
in the royal kitchen.
That is what I thought.
That is what you thought?
I am so sorry, Your Majesty.
I will never do this again.
Yes.
This is what I liked...
when I was with you.
Pardon?
Do you remember...
the day...
when I taught you...
what it really means
to become a court lady?
I will tell you...
what it means to be a court maid.
That means something like
this can happen.
And this.
What you did to me that night...
Is it what I think it is?
You were trying to start
a fight with me.
Am I correct?
But you were wrong.
I was not...
trying to start a fight with you.
This is...
what I wanted to do.
And...
this.
And I wanted...
to always...
keep you by my side like this.
(Episode 46 will air shortly.)
Step aside!
Aren't they Saheonbu's soldiers?
What's going on?
- What's happening?
- Is it really happening?
- What was that?
- Oh no.
What's going on?
This is the house of rebel Lee
Yin Jwa's father-in-law.
Letters or goods,
find anything...
to prove his guilt!
- Yes, master!
What are you doing?
His Majesty promised that there will
be no guilt by association.
How could you be innocent,
when your son-in-law was a rebel?
Capture the offender!
- Yes, master!
What did you just say?
Saheonbu seized Lee Yin Jwa's
father-in-law?
I made clear that there will be
no guilt by association.
Your Majesty.
The Chief Corrector and Professors
have arrived.
Your Majesty.
Let them enter!
(Chief Corrector:
head of Saganwon)
(Chief Professor:
head of Hongmoongwan)
I know what you're about to say.
Should I still...
listen to you?
What's the current situation?
Chief Justice.
Execute the next order by the King.
Yes, master.
(Saheonbu)
- Master.
Did you hear?
- Saheonbu...
- Where's Chief Inspector?
Where are they?
Start interrogation on Lee Yin Jwa's
father-in-law and his family.
Judicial law belongs to
the authority of Saheonbu.
Regardless of the King's order,
we will do...
Regardless of the King's order?
This is revolt and high treason.
What are you doing?
Me?
As an inspector of Saheonbu,
I'm doing my job.
I'm merely convicting the sinners...
going against the King's order.
They're getting rid of
Inspector Park from the office?
I'm still in touch
with high officials.
Jipyeong got furious
and told me to...
call the other soldiers.
- What?
- But...
it didn't sound right.
So I came here.
Inspection Leader,
we should do something.
Let's go!
We should be on Inspector
Park's side!
What should I do?
I'm not really the outgoing one.
Why did I even tell him that?
I must have gotten attached
to him recently.
Is Saheonbu on the move?
It'll start soon.
What can they do
even with the King's order?
The kingdom's executive agency
is doing its work.
The court must be empty.
Let them do the work
with just Namins.
It won't last long.
Promoting regardless of the clan?
No King ever won this fight.
No one ever succeeded.
Minister! Minister of Personnel!
What is it?
The King is totally acting up!
He's starting the fight!
What do you mean?
What's going on?
My apologies, Your Majesty.
You're appointing me
as a prime minister?
Like I said,
you'll be the prime minister,
and Jo Hyeon Myeong...
will be assigned as Chief Inspector.
Your Majesty!
No, Your Majesty.
You can't!
How could you assign...
such heavy responsibility on us?
I can't accept this either!
Then are you leaving me alone
on this road?
Is that it? Are you telling me
to do it by myself?
You know what I'm about to do.
Equity which this nation
never had.
This is...
more like a favor,
not a King's order.
I'm asking you...
to walk...
through this harsh road
with me.
(Wi Byeong Joo (Namin))
- Did you hear?
- Huh?
The court is hiring Namins,
causing chaos.
Excuse me.
Hey.
Can I ask something?
Soldiers say,
the King appointed Namins,
making chaos in the court.
Is that true?
It's none of your business.
Stay quiet.
Tell me.
Are Namins really getting a place
in the court?
So this is the story.
To stabilize the nation,
His Majesty...
is supporting appointment
of Namins.
- Oh.
- Hmm...
But look what statesmen are doing.
Both the Disciples and Patriarchs
are disobeying...
the King's order
to keep their seats.
They've never fought in the war!
Those filthy ones!
Get down! I need to speak up!
I...
lost my eldest son during a war.
They've never held a sword,
and how dare could they
act like that?
- That's right!
- He's right!
Oh, I'm the storyteller.
Wait, I also need to talk!
How long are they going to
keep arguing?
This is why only the civilians
get distressed!
- Yes!
- He's right!
He said it right!
He spoke the truth!
- Didn't he?
- He did.
I...
I have something to say too!
- Oh man.
- Listen to me carefully.
He's doing great.
Awesome.
You're better than me.
Oh goodness.
That's what they're saying?
You should have seen it.
I had no place to talk.
They've endured for too long.
They've watched a long boring
fight between the clans.
This time, the public will
become one for sure.
I'll message this to the palace.
Right away.
Yes, master.
Brother! Brother!
I found it!
Where that guy lives!
This way.
Brother.
This is the place.
Bok Dan!
Prince. We need to go now.
What are you doing?
You want to get caught?
Hurry, Prince.
No way.
Prince Milpoong?
What is it?
Can...
you pay the rest now?
- What?
- We're almost there.
The boat is ready.
You can go by yourself...
This isn't what we agreed on.
What are you doing?
What?
You've been glimpsing sideways.
Is a boat really there?
Are you fooling us?
Hey!
You're just a rebel!
Give me,
give me the money!
How dare you!
How dare you...
Yoon Yeong.
Are you okay?
Is anyone there?
Anyone?
No.
Don't make a sound.
Yoon Yeong.
It's there!
There!
The rebels I reported,
they're over there!
Yoon Yeong.
Get up.
You should go with me.
You should be with me.
You still said...
you'd make me your queen,
when I'm just a prostitute.
But I...
I never...
really loved you.
I'm sorry.
No, no.
No.
I'm sorry, Yoon Yeong.
Please don't do this to me.
I'll be there first.
Don't be scared.
I'll be waiting...
as your queen...
in another world.
So you...
should be the King...
the King...
No!
Don't leave me, Yoon Yeong.
You shouldn't leave me!
You can't!
Over there!
Prince Milpoong should be
over there!
She's here! Here's the rebel.
Prince Milpoong isn't here.
Find him!
- Yes!
Bok Dan.
[Kocowa Ver] SBS E46 'Haechi'
"The King Versus The Officials"
-♥ Ruo Xi ♥-
But I still...
can't...
let her die.
Bok Dan.
I'm Bok Dan.
What's your name?
Dal...
Dal Moon.
Is anyone...
Wake up.
What are you doing here?
Huh?
You...
didn't...
live so harshly for this.
I didn't let you go...
for this.
No!
Bok Dan...
So she...
died.
Dal Moon took care of the dead body.
Dal Moon...
They're looking for Prince Milpoong.
So,
My apologies, Your Majesty.
We have an urgent message
from Saheonbu.
How rude you are!
I said step aside.
No, we won't.
The officials of Saheonbu...
reject the new Chief Inspector.
We can't accept the new
Chief Inspector.
We won't step aside,
even if we risk our lives.
So you'll disobey the King's order?
At last, they're...
What are you doing?
Call the soldiers and...
No, you can't.
You shouldn't make a scene here.
- Master.
- Think what they'd want.
The pretext that His Majesty is
persecuting Saheonbu.
But we can't just watch.
They're holding back
on Chief Inspector.
You should.
He's enduring this indignity too.
Stop.
Officials of Saheonbu...
are blocking Chief Inspector?
My apologies, Your Majesty.
Then why did you still help me?
When you thought...
it'd be useless?
Why?
It's...
it's because...
that's real...
politics.
Moving forward might be a second.
Even if one falls back,
to move forward...
unwearyingly...
with no disappointment.
With that,
this nation...
will change...
bit by bit.
We'll move forward.
Unwearyingly...
without disappointment.
Even if...
we have to fall back.
His Majesty will arrive.
All soldiers should escort him
with perfection.
- Yes!
The King has arrived.
It's His Majesty!
- Your Majesty.
Officials of Saheonbu...
will have to open a meeting
right away.
(Cabinet meeting:
meeting of Saheonbu)
I will...
speak...
by myself.
The King has arrived!
The King...
has arrived!
I'm here!
The King...
has arrived!
Yes.
I'm the King.
I...
I am...
the King!
(Cabinet meeting)
I'm here...
by myself...
to announce...
that a new Joseon...
should commence...
from Saheonbu.
Among the agencies,
Saheonbu was especially...
ill with corruption.
Who would ever trust in Saheonbu,
and acclaim its impartiality.
Your Majesty, my apologies but...
Stop!
I'm not done yet!
But I...
will no longer...
overlook the old illness.
It's for this nation...
and all the Saheonbu officials.
Today, I announce...
to dismiss Head of Personnel,
who was in charge of
the appointment.
And I declare that...
there will be a reform...
on its...
whole system!
(Haechi)
Execute the punishment
on the sinners.
I'm innocent.
I'll walk by myself.
When the whole public stands
for the King,
what excuse do you have?
I'll keep my word...
to punish you.
A life without regret...
may be scarier than anything else.
You can't kill me.
Lee Geum!
- Your Majesty!
- I'm the King.